Experienced and talented programmer who enjoys solving problems and is highly passionate about web application development and software design. Focused and knowledgeable, with strong attention to details and ability to concentrate. Excellent critical thinking and analytical skills, with track record of being able to collaborate with others. Proven experience in creating and developing web applications, software, and solutions, and knowledgeable in several programming languages. Familiar with translating software designs and specifications into high-functioning code and incorporating software solutions into higher level systems. Able to test, debug, upgrade, and improve products and solutions for superior user experience for customers and meet business requirements as well as enhanced security and efficiency.

## Work Experience

Senior Programmer – Core Solutions 2014 – Present

- \* Incorporate business and user requirements into durable and scalable solutions.
- \* Develop code, system design, and test plans for all solutions and roll them out on both national and international levels.
- \* Support and maintain applications for web and mobile systems while ensuring solutions are secure, user-friendly, and cost-effective.
- \* Reengineer systems to improve efficiency, productivity, and accuracy for business operations.
- \* Train and mentor junior programmers on best practices and programming methodologies.

Lead Programmer – XYZ Group 2011 – 2014

- \* Programmed product enhancements and provided maintenance and support for client applications and interfaces.
- \* Conducted complex analysis and sophisticated programming to fulfill project requirements.
- \* Replaced lengthy, faulty manual processes with automated, elegant solutions.
- \* Coded new solutions that increased scalability by 70 percent and availability by 40 percent.

Programmer – OneCo 2009 – 2011

- \* Programmed web-based applications.
- \* Analyzed code for system testing and debugging.
- \* Reviewed project requirements, including objectives, input data, and output requirements.
- \* Conducted tests and modified program code as needed.
- \* Contributed to team development efforts.

## **Education and Training**

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology – 2009 ABC University, San Jose, California

## Skills

- \* Programming knowledge in Java, C++, XML, and Python
- \* Experience in developing web applications using a framework and knowledge in relational databases, such as SQL
- \* Excellent critical thinking and analytical skills
- \* Ability to collaborate with developers and business analysts to produce software designs
- \* Strong attention to details and ability to concentrate

## Hobbies and Interests

I participate in local hackathons and am a member of several gaming clubs. When not in front of a computer, I enjoy experimenting with molecular gastronomy to create innovations in food preparation and presentation. I am a fan of astronomy and often take advantage of night sky shows at local planetariums. I am also an accomplished musician, playing piano, guitar, and drums.